<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<root>
  <talks>
    <tedRank>1</tedRank>
    <tedTitle>Do schools kill creativity?</tedTitle>
    <tedAuthor>Sir Ken Robinson</tedAuthor>
    <tedTime>20:04</tedTime>
    <tedViews>11310818</tedViews>
    <tedDesc>http://www.ted.com Sir Ken Robinson makes an entertaining and profoundly moving case for creating an education system that nurtures (rather than undermines) creativity.</tedDesc>
    <tedYoutube>iG9CE55wbtY</tedYoutube>
  </talks>
  <talks>
    <tedRank>2</tedRank>
    <tedTitle>My stroke of insight</tedTitle>
    <tedAuthor>Jill Bolte Taylor</tedAuthor>
    <tedTime>20:12</tedTime>
    <tedViews>4111571</tedViews>
    <tedDesc>http://www.ted.com Neuroanatomist Jill Bolte Taylor had an opportunity few brain scientists would wish for: One morning, she realized she was having a massive stroke. As it happened -- as she felt her brain functions slip away one by one, speech, movement, understanding -- she studied and remembered every moment. </tedDesc>
    <tedYoutube>UyyjU8fzEYU</tedYoutube>
  </talks>
  <talks>
    <tedRank>3</tedRank>
    <tedTitle>The thrilling potential of SixthSense technology</tedTitle>
    <tedAuthor>Pranav Mistry</tedAuthor>
    <tedTime>15:20</tedTime>
    <tedViews>3129024</tedViews>
    <tedDesc>http://www.ted.com At TEDIndia, Pranav Mistry demos several tools that help the physical world interact with the world of data -- including a deep look at his SixthSense device and a new, paradigm-shifting paper &#x27;laptop.&#x27; In an onstage Q&amp;A, Mistry says he&#x27;ll open-source the software behind SixthSense, to open its possibilities to all.</tedDesc>
    <tedYoutube>YrtANPtnhyg</tedYoutube>
  </talks>
  <talks>
    <tedRank>4</tedRank>
    <tedTitle>Underwater astonishments</tedTitle>
    <tedAuthor>David Gallo</tedAuthor>
    <tedTime>6:01</tedTime>
    <tedViews>1037917</tedViews>
    <tedDesc>http://www.ted.com David Gallo shows jaw-dropping footage of amazing sea creatures, including a color-shifting cuttlefish, a perfectly camouflaged octopus, and a Times Square&#x27;s worth of neon light displays from fish who live in the blackest depths of the ocean.</tedDesc>
    <tedYoutube>YVvn8dpSAt0</tedYoutube>
  </talks>
  <talks>
    <tedRank>5</tedRank>
    <tedTitle>Unveiling game-changing wearable tech</tedTitle>
    <tedAuthor>Pattie Maes</tedAuthor>
    <tedTime>8:43</tedTime>
    <tedViews>1580859</tedViews>
    <tedDesc>http://www.ted.com This demo -- from Pattie Maes&#x27; lab at MIT, spearheaded by Pranav Mistry -- was the buzz of TED. It&#x27;s a wearable device with a projector that paves the way for profound interaction with our environment. Imagine &#x27;Minority Report&#x27; and then some.</tedDesc>
    <tedYoutube>nZ-VjUKAsao</tedYoutube>
  </talks>
  <talks>
    <tedRank>6</tedRank>
    <tedTitle>Why we do what we do</tedTitle>
    <tedAuthor>Tony Robbins</tedAuthor>
    <tedTime>22:31</tedTime>
    <tedViews>10044266</tedViews>
    <tedDesc>Tony Robbins discusses the &#x27;invisible forces&#x27; that make us do what we do -- and high-fives Al Gore in the front row.</tedDesc>
    <tedYoutube>Cpc-t-Uwv1I</tedYoutube>
  </talks>
  <talks>
    <tedRank>7</tedRank>
    <tedTitle>How great leaders inspire action</tedTitle>
    <tedAuthor>Simon Sinek</tedAuthor>
    <tedTime>18:35</tedTime>
    <tedViews>5415939</tedViews>
    <tedDesc>http://www.ted.com Simon Sinek presents a simple but powerful model for how leaders inspire action, starting with a golden circle and the question &#x27;Why?&#x27; His examples include Apple, Martin Luther King, and the Wright brothers -- and as a counterpoint Tivo, which (until a recent court victory that tripled its stock price) appeared to be struggling.</tedDesc>
    <tedYoutube>qp0HIF3SfI4</tedYoutube>
  </talks>
  <talks>
    <tedRank>8</tedRank>
    <tedTitle>Steve Job&#x27;s 2005 Stanford Commencement Address</tedTitle>
    <tedAuthor>Stanford</tedAuthor>
    <tedTime>15:05</tedTime>
    <tedViews>25821242</tedViews>
    <tedDesc>Drawing from some of the most pivotal points in his life, Steve Jobs, chief executive officer and co-founder of Apple Computer and of Pixar Animation Studios, urged graduates to pursue their dreams and see the opportunities in life&#x27;s setbacks -- including death itself -- at the university&#x27;s 114th Commencement on June 12, 2005.</tedDesc>
    <tedYoutube>UF8uR6Z6KLc</tedYoutube>
  </talks>
  <talks>
    <tedRank>9</tedRank>
    <tedTitle>Debunking third world myths with the bests stats you&#x27;ve ever seen</tedTitle>
    <tedAuthor>Hans Rosling</tedAuthor>
    <tedTime>20:36</tedTime>
    <tedViews>951473</tedViews>
    <tedDesc>http://www.ted.com You&#x27;ve never seen data presented like this. With the drama and urgency of a sportscaster, statistics guru Hans Rosling debunks myths about the so-called &#x27;developing world.&#x27;</tedDesc>
    <tedYoutube>RUwS1uAdUcI</tedYoutube>
  </talks>
  <talks>
    <tedRank>10</tedRank>
    <tedTitle>The power of vulnerability</tedTitle>
    <tedAuthor>Brene Brown</tedAuthor>
    <tedTime>20:50</tedTime>
    <tedViews>5570469</tedViews>
    <tedDesc>http://www.ted.com Brené Brown studies human connection -- our ability to empathize, belong, love. In a poignant, funny talk at TEDxHouston, she shares a deep insight from her research, one that sent her on a personal quest to know herself as well as to understand humanity. A talk to share.</tedDesc>
    <tedYoutube>iCvmsMzlF7o</tedYoutube>
  </talks>
  <talks>
    <tedRank>11</tedRank>
    <tedTitle>The puzzle of motivation</tedTitle>
    <tedAuthor>Dan Pink</tedAuthor>
    <tedTime>18:37</tedTime>
    <tedViews>5598866</tedViews>
    <tedDesc>http://www.ted.com Career analyst Dan Pink examines the puzzle of motivation, starting with a fact that social scientists know but most managers don&#x27;t: Traditional rewards aren&#x27;t always as effective as we think. Listen for illuminating stories -- and maybe, a way forward.</tedDesc>
    <tedYoutube>rrkrvAUbU9Y</tedYoutube>
  </talks>
  <talks>
    <tedRank>12</tedRank>
    <tedTitle>Lightning calculation and other &#x27;mathemagic&#x27;</tedTitle>
    <tedAuthor>Arthur Benjamin</tedAuthor>
    <tedTime>15:15</tedTime>
    <tedViews>1164738</tedViews>
    <tedDesc>http://www.ted.com In a lively show, mathemagician Arthur Benjamin races a team of calculators to figure out 3-digit squares, solves another massive mental equation and guesses a few birthdays. How does he do it? He&#x27;ll tell you.</tedDesc>
    <tedYoutube>M4vqr3_ROIk</tedYoutube>
  </talks>
  <talks>
    <tedRank>13</tedRank>
    <tedTitle>Your elusive creative genius</tedTitle>
    <tedAuthor>Elizabeth Gilbert</tedAuthor>
    <tedTime>19:29</tedTime>
    <tedViews>2787426</tedViews>
    <tedDesc>&#x27;Eat, Pray, Love&#x27; author Elizabeth Gilbert muses on the impossible things we expect from artists and geniuses -- and shares the radical idea that, instead of the rare person &#x27;being&#x27; a genius, all of us &#x27;have&#x27; a genius. It&#x27;s a funny, personal and surprisingly moving talk.</tedDesc>
    <tedYoutube>86x-u-tz0MA</tedYoutube>
  </talks>
  <talks>
    <tedRank>14</tedRank>
    <tedTitle>Why are we happy? Why aren&#x27;t we happy?</tedTitle>
    <tedAuthor>Dan Gilbert</tedAuthor>
    <tedTime>22:03</tedTime>
    <tedViews>1306240</tedViews>
    <tedDesc>http://www.ted.com Dan Gilbert, author of Stumbling on Happiness, challenges the idea that well be miserable if we dont get what we want. Our &#x27;psychological immune system&#x27; lets us feel truly happy even when things don&#x27;t go as planned.</tedDesc>
    <tedYoutube>LTO_dZUvbJA</tedYoutube>
  </talks>
  <talks>
    <tedRank>15</tedRank>
    <tedTitle>Questioning the universe</tedTitle>
    <tedAuthor>Stephen Hawking</tedAuthor>
    <tedTime>10:13</tedTime>
    <tedViews>5474352</tedViews>
    <tedDesc>http://www.ted.com Professor Stephen Hawking asks some big questions about our universe -- How did the universe begin? How did life begin? Are we alone? -- and discusses how we might go about answering them.</tedDesc>
    <tedYoutube>xjBIsp8mS-c</tedYoutube>
  </talks>
  <talks>
    <tedRank>16</tedRank>
    <tedTitle>Unveiling the genius of multi-touch interface design</tedTitle>
    <tedAuthor>Jeff Han</tedAuthor>
    <tedTime>10:12</tedTime>
    <tedViews>270552</tedViews>
    <tedDesc>http://www.ted.com Jeff Han shows off a cheap, scalable multi-touch and pressure-sensitive computer screen interface that may spell the end of point-and-click.</tedDesc>
    <tedYoutube>ac0E6deG4AU</tedYoutube>
  </talks>
  <talks>
    <tedRank>17</tedRank>
    <tedTitle>Wii remote hacks</tedTitle>
    <tedAuthor>Johnny Lee</tedAuthor>
    <tedTime>6:14</tedTime>
    <tedViews>1551198</tedViews>
    <tedDesc>http://www.ted.com Johnny Lee demos his amazing Wii Remote hacks, which transform the $40 game piece into a digital whiteboard, a touchscreen and a head-mounted 3-D viewer. A multi-ovation demo from TED2008.</tedDesc>
    <tedYoutube>QgKCrGvShZs</tedYoutube>
  </talks>
  <talks>
    <tedRank>18</tedRank>
    <tedTitle>Brain magic</tedTitle>
    <tedAuthor>Keith Barry</tedAuthor>
    <tedTime>19:50</tedTime>
    <tedViews>5815575</tedViews>
    <tedDesc>http://www.ted.com First, Keith Barry shows us how our brains can fool our bodies -- in a trick that works via podcast too. Then he involves the audience in some jaw-dropping (and even a bit dangerous) feats of brain magic.</tedDesc>
    <tedYoutube>GigYWy2UmOY</tedYoutube>
  </talks>
  <talks>
    <tedRank>19</tedRank>
    <tedTitle>10 things you didn&#x27;t know about orgasm</tedTitle>
    <tedAuthor>Mary Roach</tedAuthor>
    <tedTime>17:12</tedTime>
    <tedViews>5568632</tedViews>
    <tedDesc>http://www.ted.com &#x27;Bonk&#x27; author Mary Roach delves into obscure scientific research, some of it centuries old, to make 10 surprising claims about sexual climax, ranging from the bizarre to the hilarious. (This talk is aimed at adults. Viewer discretion advised.)</tedDesc>
    <tedYoutube>7jx0dTYUO5E</tedYoutube>
  </talks>
  <talks>
    <tedRank>20</tedRank>
    <tedTitle>Robots that fly ... and cooperate</tedTitle>
    <tedAuthor>Vijay Kumar</tedAuthor>
    <tedTime>16:47</tedTime>
    <tedViews>1770282</tedViews>
    <tedDesc>http://www.ted.com In his lab at Penn, Vijay Kumar and his team build flying quadrotors, small, agile robots that swarm, sense each other, and form ad hoc teams -- for construction, surveying disasters and far more.</tedDesc>
    <tedYoutube>4ErEBkj_3PY</tedYoutube>
  </talks>
  <talks>
    <tedRank>21</tedRank>
    <tedTitle>The good news about PMS</tedTitle>
    <tedAuthor>Robyn Stein DeLuca</tedAuthor>
    <tedTime>14:49</tedTime>
    <tedViews>150408</tedViews>
    <tedDesc>Everybody knows that most women go a little crazy right before they get their period, that their reproductive hormones cause their emotions to fluctuate wildly. Except: There&#x27;s very little scientific consensus about premenstrual syndrome. Says psychologist Robyn Stein DeLuca, science doesn&#x27;t agree on the definition, cause, treatment or even existence of PMS. She explores what we know and don&#x27;t know about it — and why the popular myth has persisted. </tedDesc>
    <tedYoutube>aI8KiPiVLyY</tedYoutube>
  </talks>
  <talks>
    <tedRank>22</tedRank>
    <tedTitle>Why we laugh</tedTitle>
    <tedAuthor>Sophie Scott</tedAuthor>
    <tedTime>17:09</tedTime>
    <tedViews>221290</tedViews>
    <tedDesc>Did you know that you&#x27;re 13 times more likely to laugh if you&#x27;re with somebody else than if you&#x27;re alone? Cognitive neuroscientist Sophie Scott shares this and other surprising facts about laughter in this fast-paced, action-packed and, yes, hilarious dash through the science of the topic.</tedDesc>
    <tedYoutube>UxLRv0FEndM</tedYoutube>
  </talks>
</root>